Ricketts mss. III, 1856-1979 LMC 1831
Lilly Library
- Subject Files
  - Portraits - Proofs of composite etchings of men (Box 36)
    Unidentified etchings by C. L. Ricketts, presumably for periodicals such as Self Culture
  - Portraits - 26 individuals (Box 36)
    Comprising 39 photographs, proofs, etchings, etc., of Fields, Lyman Gage, Gray, Horton, and John D. Rockefeller in 1896; others unidentified
  - Vinycomb, John
    1833-1928, calligrapher
    - Biographical material, 1893-1909 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Biographical sketch by CLR (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Photographs (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Bookplates and heraldic shields (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Illuminations (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Writings (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - Photograph - Vinycomb at desk (Box 36)
  - About books (Box 26, Folder 11)
    Poems, quotations, and clippings about the worth, meaning and value of owning books
  - Art - news clippings (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - Art - leaflets and pamphlets (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - Bookplates (Box 26, Folder 14)
    Clippings about bookplates, of bookplates, and of ideas for designs for bookplates
  - Books, manuscripts, and the art of writing - news clippings (Box 26, Folder 15)
  - Books, manuscripts, and the art of writing - leaflets and pamphlets (Box 26, Folder 16)
  - Books and libraries - news clippings (Box 39)
  - Business and finance, 1924-1931 (Box 26, Folder 17)
    Clippings and circulars, chiefly about investing in stocks and bonds, including Union Carbide
  - Cancelled stamps (Box 54)
  - Coler, George Perry (Box 26, Folder 18)
    1853?-1915, educator [lb] [fill in from binder]
  - Cookery (Box 26, Folder 19)
  - Emblems and seals (Box 26, Folder 21)
    Collected materials for and about emblems and seals, including clippings and pictures useful for ideas
  - Greeting cards (Box 26, Folder 27)
    These may or may not have been designed by CLR, or perhaps used by him as ideas for illuminations
  - Health and beauty (Box 26, Folder 28)
    Clippings and leaflets regarding health practices
  - Leaflets and pamphlets, A-D (Box 26, Folder 29)
  - Leaflets and pamphlets, F-M (Box 26, Folder 30)
  - Leaflets and pamphlets, N-Z (Box 26, Folder 31)
  - News clippings, 1884-1910 (Box 26, Folder 32)
  - News clippings, 1911-1970 (Box 26, Folder 33)
  - News clippings, undated (Box 26, Folder 34)
  - Northwestern University (Box 26, Folder 35)
    Pictures of buildings and insiginias for fraternities and classes
  - Osborn, Albert Sherman (Box 26, Folder 36)
  - Photoengraving (Box 26, Folder 37)
  - Real estate (Box 27, Folder 3)
    Clippings and map of Chicago
  - Sales catalogs (folder 1), 1878-1940 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    Clippings from catalogs regarding books and manuscripts
  - Sales catalogs (folder 2) (Box 27, Folder 5)
    Typed and holograph references regarding sales of books and manuscripts
  - Sangorski, Alberta (Box 36)
    1862-1932, calligrapher
    Lincoln's Speeches and Whitman's "O Captain! My Captain!": black and white sets of photographs of manuscript "designed, written out and illuminated" by Alberta Sangorski for presentation to Henry Horner, Governor of Illinois
  - Tomkins, Thomas (Box 27, Folder 6)
    1743-1816. Trade card
  - Heraldic designs (Box 36)
  - Scribes (Box 37)
    Representations of scribes at work, chiefly from medieval documents
- Writings and Book/Manuscript Collections
  - Bibliographies (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - List of books in a private library (Box 27, Folder 11)
    Includes Fiction, Poetry, Drama, Children's Books, Health, History, and Schoolbooks. Occasional holograph additions in ink in hand of Julia Ricketts King
  - Calligraphy and writing books
    - American references (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - English and European references (Box 27, Folder 13)
    - European references (Box 27, Folder 14)
    - Holograph notes by CLR, 2 Folders (Box 27, Folder 15)
      Accompanied in Folder 2 by list of calligraphers and engravers, arranged by country, Jan. 1924
    - The Ricketts Collection of Calligraphy and Writing Books, English section and supplement (Box 27, Folder 16)
    - The Ricketts Collection of Calligraphy and Writing Books, German section (Box 27, Folder 17)
    - The Ricketts Collection of Calligraphy and Writing Books, Spanish section (Box 27, Folder 18)
  - Coler, Cyphron Seymour, 1858-1944
    - Poems, 1887-1930 (Box 27, Folder 19)
      Collected verses, and those enclosed with letters
    - Prose (Box 27, Folder 20)
      The Yellowstone National Park. Accompanied by envelope to Prof. C. L. Ricketts at Chicago, 1887, Oct. 19
  - Davenport, Cyril James Humphries, 1848-1941
    - Correspondence and notes (Box 27, Folder 21)
      Correspondence between Ricketts and Davenport about the proposed work on Roger Payne for the Caxton Club
    - "Roger Payne," typescript with holograph corrections, 1925 (Box 27, Folder 22)
      Copied from Major Cyril Davenport. Proofing by John T. Lee
    - "Roger Payne," typescript marked "Original" (Box 27, Folder 23)
    - "Roger Payne," typescript marked "Carbon" (Box 27, Folder 24)
    - "Even the most casual observer…", 1914 (Box 27, Folder 25)
      No author. Concerns the contribution of P. H. van Gestel of Amsterdam to penmanship. States that he was born July 8, 1864. Includes list of his writings, all in Dutch
  - Field, Marshall (Box 54)
    - Photostats of the illuminated mansuscript and letters presented to Marshall Field by the Citizens Committee, 1944; 4 Copies (Box 54)
    - Photostats of the illuminated manuscript... (Text only), 1944 (Box 54)
  - Fonert, Mark
    - "Most majestic and dignified lady…" (Box 27, Folder 26)
  - King, Jasper Seymour
    - The Age of Golden Books / The Golden Age of Books (Box 27, Folder 29)
    - Can American Dem'y [Democracy] Survive? (Box 27, Folder 30)
    - Collected notes about Coella Lindsay Ricketts (Box 27, Folder 31)
    - The Great Art of the Illuminated Mss. (Box 27, Folder 32)
    - March 4, 1932 And After (Box 27, Folder 33)
      Poem regarding Franklin Delano Roosevelt
    - Notes, miscellaneous (Box 27, Folder 34)
      Assortment of notes in the hand of Jasper Seymour King
    - Suggestions for Presentation of the Fourth Stanza of the S.S.B. to Chicago Symphony Audiences (Box 27, Folder 35)
      Concerns the Star Spangled Banner
    - When we wonder how "we get this way" (Box 27, Folder 36)
  - King, Julia (Ricketts)
    - Collected Notes on the Art of Writing (Box 27, Folder 37)
    - Notes, miscellaneous (Box 27, Folder 38)
      An assortment of notes, chiefly in the hand of Julia Ricketts King or collected by her
    - Notes on a Bibliophile (Box 27, Folder 39)
      Biographical sketch of C. L. Ricketts given for the Winnetka Fortnightly
  - Koehler, Emma E[milie]
    Koehler, Director of Big Brother and Big Sister League, Chicago
    - Lines Suggested by Mr. C. L. Rickett's Scriptorium, 1 March 1912 (Box 27, Folder 40)
  - Manson, Alfred Small
    - Catalog of Books on Penmanship, April 1875 (Box 27, Folder 41)
  - Miller, John Stocker
    1888-1965, lawyer
    - Poems of Youth (Box 27, Folder 42)
  - Miscellaneous notes on books and manuscripts, 1892-1933 (Box 27, Folder 43)
  - Miscellaneous notes on books and manuscripts, undated (Box 27, Folder 44)
  - Ricci, Seymour de, 1881-1942
    - List of manuscripts of C. Lindsay Ricketts Collection, compiled for the Union Cataog of Manuscripts (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - List of manuscripts of C. Lindsay Ricketts Collection (copy 2) (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - List of manuscripts of C. Lindsay Ricketts Collection (copy 3) (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - List of manuscripts of C. Lindsay Ricketts Collection (copy 4) (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - List of manuscripts of C. Lindsay Ricketts Collection - notes by Ricketts on Ricci's catalog (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Ricketts, Coella Lindsay
    - Address read before the Western Society of Drawing and Writing teachers, December 1900 (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Album of penmanship samples, August 1876 (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Char-Man Wilson, The Piper at the Gates of Dawn (Box 28, Folder 8)
      Char-Man is Woodrow Wilson, about to be inaugurated as president
    - "Controlling influence" (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - Notebooks regarding medieval manuscripts (Box 28, Folder 10)
      Perhaps kept during Ricketts' journeys to Europe
    - New Era System Copy Book (folder 1) (Box 28, Folder 12)
      Proofs of material, some of which were used for back cover of copy book: one for Semi-Slant and 5 for Vertical Writing
    - New Era System Copy Book (folder 2) (Box 28, Folder 13)
      Concerned with production and sales of New Era System Copybooks
    - New Era System of Semi-Slant Writing (Books 1-6), 6 Folders (Box 37)
    - New Era System of Vertical Writing (Books 1-6), 6 Folders (Box 37)
    - Notes on manuscripts in Durham Library, England, 1912-1926 (Box 28, Folder 14)
    - Penmanship, Part One, ca. 1895 (Box 28, Folder 15)
    - Poems (Box 28, Folder 16)
    - Roman Alphabet (Box 28, Folder 17)
      For further information on this endeavor, see correspondence of Ricketts with Bruce Rogers and Frederick W. Goudy; and letters, 1928, July 7 (from J. H. Jansen); Sept. 21 (W. E. Rueller); Oct. 25 (CLR to Goudy); Nov. 1 (CLR to Goudy); and 1929, July 18, 22; Aug. 13; Sept. 13, 27
    - The Story of an Ancient Art - draft 1 (Box 28, Folder 18)
    - The Story of an Ancient Art - draft 2 (Box 28, Folder 19)
    - The Story of an Ancient Art - draft 3 (Box 28, Folder 20)
    - The Story of an Ancient Art - draft 4 (Box 28, Folder 21)
    - The Story of an Ancient Art - draft 5 (Box 28, Folder 22)
    - The Story of an Ancient Art - draft 6 (Box 28, Folder 23)
    - The Story of an Ancient Art - draft 7 (Box 28, Folder 24)
    - The Story of an Ancient Art - draft 8 (Box 28, Folder 25)
      Accompanied by instruction pages in ink for placement of initials, and by copy of printed page from DeRicci Census about the Ricketts Collection
    - The Story of an Ancient Art - illuminated pages (Box 28, Folder 26)
    - The Story of an Ancient Art - Illuminated title page in color and initials (Box 37)
    - Why No Two People Write Alike, 1918 (Box 28, Folder 27)
  - The Ricketts Collection
    - Cataloging and work records of Arthur Jefferies Collins, John Alexander Herbert, Robert Steele, William Jerome Wilson, and Francis Wormald, 1930-1932 (Box 28, Folder 28)
    - Cataloging and work records of J. A. Herbert (Box 28, Folder 29)
    - Cataloging and work records of Robert Steele (Box 28, Folder 30)
    - A Description (Box 28, Folder 31)
      Some notes in the hand of Jasper King
    - English manuscripts and French, German, Dutch, Italian, Asian, Spanish (Box 28, Folder 32)
    - Labels (Box 28, Folder 33)
    - Manuscripts and calligraphy books (Box 28, Folder 34)
    - Miscellaneous group of manuscripts (Box 28, Folder 35)
    - Notes collected on books (Box 28, Folder 36)
      These may refer to books owned by CLR, to books wanted, or to books seen
    - Notes collected on manuscripts, 8 Folders (Box 28, Folder 37)
  - Schoppmeyer, Ansgar
    - Die Technik des Reliefgoldes (Box 28, Folder 38)
  - Steele
    This may or may not be the Robert Steele, 1860-1944, who did cataloging for CLR
    - Half-Forgotten Stories (Box 28, Folder 40)
  - Waterman, Nixon, 1859-1944
    - A Rose to the Living (Box 28, Folder 41)
  - Wilson, William Jerome, 1884-1963
    - For Tom: Leaf from an antiphonary… (Box 28, Folder 42)
  - Winnetka Educational Press
    - About Cursive Writing (Box 28, Folder 43)
- Medieval Fragments and Illuminations
  - Photographs and Modern Holograph Reproductions
    Arranged by library or collector. Many photographs bear research notes by Ricketts. Some reproductions bear notes concerning the length of time to complete: e.g., "12 days"
    - Notes, 2 Folders (Box 20, Folder 2-3)
      Contain notes by C. L. Ricketts and others
    - Lord Aldenham's Library (Box 34)
    - Berlin (Box 34)
    - Bodleian Library, Oxford (Box 34)
    - British Museum (Box 34)
    - Brussels - Bibliotheque (Box 33)
    - Cambridge - Corpus Christi College (Box 33)
    - Cambridge - Pembroke College (Box 33)
    - Cambridge - St. Johns College (Box 33)
    - Cambridge - Trinity College (Box 33)
    - Cambridge - University Library (Box 33)
    - Cockerell, Sydney C. mss. (Box 33)
    - Douai, France - Public Library (Box 33)
    - Durham Cathedral Library (Box 33)
    - Edinburgh - National Library (Box 33)
    - Fitzwilliam Museum - Cambridge (Box 33)
    - Grolier Club (Box 31)
    - Hoe, Robert mss. (Box 31)
    - London (Box 31)
    - Munich (Box 31)
    - Newberry Library (Box 31)
    - Oxford - All Souls College (Box 31)
    - Oxford - Christ Church (Box 31)
    - Oxford - New College (Box 31)
    - Paris - Bibliotheque Nationale (Box 31)
    - Perrins, C. Dyson mss. (Box 31)
    - Rylands Library - Manchester (Box 31)
    - Salisbury Cathedral (Box 32)
    - Trinity College - Dublin (Box 32)
    - Vatican Library (Box 32)
    - Victoria and Albert Museum (Box 32)
    - Vienna (Box 32)
    - Winchester, Dean and Chapter (Box 32)
    - Unidentified leaves and alphabets (Box 32)
  - Facsimiles and prints (Box 26, Folder 22)
    Specimens of medieval documents, illuminated, and modern pieces in illuminated medieval style [fill in from binder]
  - Facsimiles of illuminated manuscripts (Box 38)
  - Facsimiles of bindings (Box 38)
  - Illuminations, 19th century (Box 50)
    Chiefly Irish
    Arranged principally by honoree
  - 1. From Luzac & Co., London, undated; Vellums (Box 29)
    6 fragments with a few words; 6 fragments with ruled lines; 3 whole pages of ruled lines; 1 set of 5 pages of ruled lines
  - 2. Missale?, 13th century?; 1 leaf, vellum. 25 x 18 cm (Box 29)
    Text in red and black with 7 penwork initials. Remnants of leather thongs at top and bottom to serve as portfolio. Traces of another hand in margin. Latin
  - 3. Text: Nicene Creed and Ten Commandments, undated; 1 leaf, vellum. 12 x 8.5 cm (Box 29)
    Text contains portions of the Nicene Creed and Ten Commandments. Empty space for large initial, with nearby decoration in blue, gold, and red. French
  - 4. Initials B and S, undated; 2 fragments, vellum. B: 17.5 x 13 cm; S: 17 x 13 cm (Box 29)
    Illuminated in blue and orange with dragons, a figure, and ornaments. Cut from work with musical notation
  - 5. Initials I and O, undated; 2 fragments, vellum. 6.5 x 6.5 cm (Box 29)
    Size refers to the initial only; elongated decorated portion cut out following its lines extends to 20 cm and 10.5 cm respectively. Heavy gold, blue, green, and red. Cut from work with musical notation
  - 6. Initials G and N, undated; 2 fragments, vellum. 24 x 16.5 cm (Box 29)
    G in pink, red, blue and green scroll work. N in pink, red, blue, green and gold with haloed figure holding a book; verso has A and T in red and blue penwork. Cut from work with musical notation
  - 7. Border, undated; 1 fragment, vellum. 11 x 6 cm (Box 29)
    Floriated in blue, green, purple, with traces of gold. Verso blank
  - 8. Initials C and O, undated; 2 fragments, vellum. C: 10.5 x 11 cm; O: 22.5 x 10 cm (Box 29)
    O ends in a long scroll/floral design. In pink, blue, red, green. Cut from work with musical notation
  - 9. Initial M, undated; 1 fragment, vellum. 10 x 10 cm (Box 29)
    Two full length bearded men with haloes in panels within the initial of blue, red and green. Cut from work with musical notation
  - 10. Les Commandemens de Dieu, undated; Vellum. 15.5 x 18.5 cm (Box 29)
    Text with floriated gold initial A; other initials in red, blue, gold, and black; set in two panels outlined in gold against a black border. Verso blank. French
  - 11. Missale?, undated; Leaves 67 and 68, vellum. 6.5 x 14.5 cm, presumably cut from original work and set in larger pages of 19 x 14 cm (Box 29)
    Marginal lines of gold; leaf 68 has initial O in white against gold. Adjunct leaves still retain cord used in binding
  - 12. Devotional, undated; Leaf 15?, vellum, 11 x 8 cm.
    Large initial N in blue against gold with strawberry border with two patterned "comma" designs at top; verso with text and blue and red initials, no border. German
  - 13. Horae? Leaves 9 and 15?, undated; 12.5 x 9.5 cm (Box 29)
    Leaves pasted together. Initial O in red encircling madonna and child against gold; floriated border with [coat of arms?] at lower edge on leaf 15; leaf 9 with initials in red and blue ink. Coloring eroded. Latin
  - 14. Miniature of the Martyrdom of the Infants, undated; 1 leaf, vellum. 19 x 13.5 cm (Box 29)
    Herod on throne, two soldiers killing children, protesting father, set in a border of strawberries, parakeets and scrolls. Brief text below miniature. Verso lists table of contents. French
  - 15. Exposition on the Trinity, undated; 1 leaf, vellum. 16 x 10 cm (Box 29)
    Two columns; left and middle borders in pink and blue; initials in gold, blue and red; scrolls and leaves top and bottom. Staining. Latin
  - 16. The Psalms, undated; 4 fragments, vellum. 18.5 x 13 cm, original size (Box 29)
    Religious text containing the Psalms, including 1 complete leaf of the volume. Single column, 21 lines. One ornate penwork initial, other smaller initials. Badly stained from use as pastedown for book
  - 17. Hymnal?, undated; 1 leaf, vellum. 28.5 x 20 cm (Box 29)
    Twelve staves with words, and words for 13th stave at top. Red and blue penwork initials. Verso badly eroded, from use as pastedown? Latin
  - 18. Initials E and S, undated; 2 fragments, vellum. 14 x 12 cm (Box 29)
    Decoration extends length to 27.5 and 34 cm respectively. Cut out and mounted on boards 31 and 34 cm respectively. Colors of red, blue, green against gold
  - 19. Liber Precum Franciae, 15th century; 1 leaf, vellum. 16 x 12 cm (Box 29)
    One column, 14 lines. Accompanied by dealer description. French
  - 20. Graduale, Leaves 112 and 119, 14th century; 31.5 x 23 cm (Box 29)
    Adjunct leaves. Decorated initials in red, blue, and black penwork. Accompanied by dealer description. Latin
  - 21. Devotional, undated; 4 leaves, vellum (Box 29)
    Separate leaves. Initials (2 M's and 2 N's) of heavy gold against pink and blue with white tracery. Floriated borders in gold, green, blue, yellow. Dutch
  - 22. Horae?, undated; 1 leaf, vellum (Box 29)
    Miniature of madonna and child in blue with gold haloes seated on bench under canopy. Face of madonna and figure of child either unfinished or eroded. Floriated border in colors and gold. Initial O in blue against gold. Verso has text only. Latin
  - 23. Horae?, undated; 1 leaf, vellum (Box 29)
    Miniature of King David in blue robe and gold crown at prayer with gold lyre at his knee, heavenly figure in upper left-hand corner. Initial D in pink against blue with gold decoration. Text on recto eroded; text and small initials on verso. Latin
  - 24. Psalms 109-118, undated; 1 leaf, vellum. 21 x 13 cm (Box 29)
    Historiated initial D with figures of two men both with books and the Holy Spirit overhead. Latin text compares favorably with that of the 1551 Bible (Lilly PS75 1551a). Red and blue penwork scrolls and flourishes. Latin
  - 25. Timothy, Ch. 1-6, undated; 1 leaf, vellum. 18 x 13 cm (Box 29)
    Historiated initial P of man with book ending in dragon tail, in gold and blue. Red and blue penwork initials. Latin
  - 26. Initials: D, E, I, L, N, O (2), Q, undated; 8 fragments, vellum. 10.5/13 x 12.5/13 cm (Box 29)
    Blue and red intricate penwork with touches of gold. Cut from work with musical notation
  - 27. Initial G, undated; 1 fragment, vellum. 12 x 14 cm (Box 29)
    Initial size: 4.5 x 4.5 cm. Blue and red intricate penwork. Cut from work with musical notation. Stamped: Malcotti, via Toselli, 42
  - 28. Unidentified medieval fragment A, undated; 1 fragment, paper. 17.5 x 8 cm (Box 29)
    In cursive French? Edges need straightening
  - 29. Unidentified medieval fragment B, undated; 2 fragments, vellum. 16.5 x 20.5 cm (Box 29)
    Exposition on religious matters with reference to the pope, bishops and women. Marginal scribblings in black ink in another hand. Formerly used as bookbinding. Latin
  - 30. Unidentified medieval fragment C, undated; 1 fragment, vellum. 6 x 19 cm (Box 29)
    Two columns of text. Red initials. Stained and eroded text. Latin
  - 31. Unidentified medieval fragment D, undated; 1 fragment, vellum. 12.5 x 5 cm (Box 29)
    Red and black lettering; lettering eroded on verso. Latin
  - 32. Borders, undated; 7 fragments, vellum. 10.5/17.5 x 2.5/4.5 cm (Box 29)
    Floriated in blue, rose, yellow, green and gold. Cut from same work. Verso blank except two with blue and red penwork
  - 33. Unidentified medieval fragment E, undated; 6 fragments, vellum. 6/23 x 14.25 cm (Box 29)
    Probably cut from same document, pages 4, 51, 78 and 148 (or 150). Two, blank; two with words and musical notation (4 and 51); one with words only (78), and one with single word: loquetur
  - 34. Unidentified medieval fragment F, undated; 1 fragment, vellum. 26 x 14.5 cm (Box 29)
    Initials A, M, O in red and blue penwork; E in black and green. Words and musical notation on one side, text on the other. One line eroded
  - 35. Miniature of Royal Wedding, undated; 1 leaf, vellum. 10 x 14.5 cm (Box 29)
    11.3 x 16.3 cm overall. Archbishop? officiating. Groom in red robe, bride in blue with green headdress, men and nuns as guests, drum and two horns as instruments, feast in preparation in background. Verso blank
  - 36. Miniature of the Angel and the Shepherds, undated; 1 fragment, vellum. 9.5 x 6.5 cm (Box 29)
    Two shepherds, 9 sheep, and the angel announcing the birth of Christ, cut from religious text. Six small initials on verso in gold, red, and blue. Latin
  - 37. Miniature of Jesus in the synagogue teaching the Elders, undated; 1 fragment, vellum. 8.5 x 10 cm (Box 29)
    Joseph and Mary in the background. Colors of red, blue, green, gold, gray pillars, brown bench. Cut from work with musical notation
  - 38. Initials A and B, undated; 2 fragments, vellum. 8 x 6.5 cm (Box 29)
    In red with gold and penwork decoration. Cut from work with musical notation
  - 39. Initial T, 15th century; 1 fragment, vellum. 7.8 x 8.3 cm (Box 29)
    In red and blue with red and blue penwork. Cut from work with musical notation. Acquired from E. Backus in 1924, as Flemish, xvth century. See note with No. 40. Flemish
  - 40. Initial U, 15th century; 1 fragment, vellum. 9.3 x 10 cm (Box 29)
    In red and blue with decoration in green and red. Cut from work with musical notation. Acquired from E. Backus in 1924, as Flemish, 15th cent. Flemish
  - 41. Initial P, undated; 1 fragment, vellum. 10.5 x 6 cm (Box 29)
    In red with purple penwork decoration. Cut from work with musical notation with 6.5 cm width between lines of the stave
  - 42. Illumination, undated; 1 fragment, vellum. 8.7 x 2/4.5 cm (Box 29)
    Remnant of an illuminated initial with 3 birds and a fox, cut out along the lines of the design. In blue, red, and gold. Portion of a letter of the alphabet on verso
  - 43. Initial M, undated; 1 fragment, vellum. 8 x 13 cm (Box 29)
    In red with blue penwork. Cut from religious text
  - 44. Initials O, E, A, N, E, undated; 1 fragment, vellum. 14.5 x 5.5 cm (Box 29)
    In blue and red with red and blue penwork. Text on recto; verso eroded
  - 45. Initials H, O, and S, undated; 3 fragments, vellum (Box 29)
    Each in heavy gold with heavy gold borders. H - 8 x 8 cm against a background of a flaming heart. O - 9 x 8 cm against scenic background of grass, trees, and blue sky. S - 9 x 8 cm against a scene of two men appearing before a judge or ruler, to 3 attendants. All with musical notation on verso. Acquired from Theophile Belin, Paris
  - 46. Illumination, undated; 3 fragments, vellum (Box 29)